wuqin@wustl.edu | Gainesville, FL

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Information System Management new graduate seeks software engineer opportunities, with sufficient project experience in web development and machine learning; Quickly learn and master new technologies; equally successful in both team and self-directed settings.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Washington University in St. Louis

Master of Information system management

• GPA: 3.87/4.00

• Major Courses: Data Mining, Optimization, Introduction to Cybersecurity, IT Architecture and Infrastructure, Enterprise Data Management, Applied Data Science for Practitioner

Sichuan Agricultural University

Ya'an, China

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Technology

2015/09 - 2019/06

Saint Louis, Missouri

2019/08 - 2021/01

Average Scores: 87.8/100.0

 Major Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Algorithms Analysis and Design, Principle and Application of Database, Software Engineering, Computer Network

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

GoParks Web Application

2021/01 - 2021/04

- Designed and implemented GoParks website that supports CRUD operations for users, parks and reviews depending on a user's authorization/ownership.
- Utilized RESTful architecture with Bootstrap 5 for styling; developed the backend using Node.js and Express framework; implemented MongoDB Atlas to store archives in cloud.
- Integrated Mapbox to provide parks' information and link on map based on the locations.
- Designed flash messages handling error and success results to provide users with feedback.
- Hashed password using a cryptographic salt by Passport.js to enhance the authentication mechanism.

Regression and classification analysis on UCI wine dataset

2020/03 – 2020/04

- Preprocessed dataset by data cleaning, categorical feature transformation, missing value filling and standardization, etc.
- Executed linear regression, lasso regression and random forest to analyze the 14 chemical information variables of wine; obtained the model to calculate the predicted value;
- Implemented logistic regression, K-nearest neighbor algorithm and self-built model to learn the training set and evaluated the model through the average absolute error.
- Refined the model by finding the best parameters using grid search. The final accuracy rate reached 99.8%.

MINST Handwritten dataset

2019/10 - 2019/11

- Applied Keras package to deploy the convolutional neural network; customized a VAE model; calculated the mean and variance of each number k; constructed normal distributions and performed sampling reconstruction.
- Customized a convolutional layer to calculate the loss between input image and decoded image.
- Applied cosine similarity comparison method to compare the similarity of the images; modified the number of dimensions and layers to generate the best parameters of the model.

Leadership Experience

Director of Propaganda Dept., Association of SAU Clubs

2016/05 - 2017/06

- Responsible for the new club member recruitment in the 2016 Hundred Regiment Campaign. Recruit nearly 10,000 participants. Design and issue 1,000 brochures for the activity.
- Participate in discussions and decision-making with the instructor and the Bureau of the Social Federation, and responsible for the overall arrangement of departmental work.
- Propose and implement the WeChat Official Account for the Association; Take charge of daily management of the account and gain 2000 followers during one-year's operations.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Programming languages: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Linux, MATLAB
- Tools: MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, Bootstrap5, Ajax, jQuery, Visual Studio, Git/GitHub, Hadoop, Tableau

portfolio: http://oneariaaa.github.io